alientechnology.com 2006-12-06

# Alien Technology - Privacy Policy

Collectively, the terms below are referred to as the "Agreement." Alien Technology Corporation and its affiliates worldwide (collectively "ALIEN") are committed to taking reasonable steps necessary to protect your privacy. Once you choose to provide your "personal data" to ALIEN (any information by which you can be individually identified), ALIEN will endeavor to make sure it is only used in connection with your business relationship with ALIEN. However, by submitting personal data to ALIEN, you indicate that you consent to ALIEN's use of such data as described within the scope of this Privacy Policy. Should you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, however, feel free to direct these to ALIEN at [privacy@alientechnology.com](mailto:privacy@alientechnology.com).

Purpose of Collection

ALIEN may in the course of business collect personal data that is voluntarily provided by you at our web site. When you provide personal data to ALIEN, ALIEN will usually inform you of the purposes for which it is being collected. The potential uses include, among others, providing requested information or educational materials, providing ALIEN services via online access, or training or educational activities. Our policy is not to share personal data with unrelated companies, except as provided for in this Agreement or as described at the time of collection or as necessary in connection with internal information processing activities. We recognize that your data is confidential and we will take all reasonable measures to protect your data while it is in our possession. 

Collection of Personal Data by ALIEN

When you submit your personal data at this web site in response to a registration form or while accessing applications located at this web site, the data controller/administrator collecting the personal data for purposes described is Alien Technology Corporation, a Deleware, USA company. ALIEN normally only requests limited business-related personal data, such as name, title, company address, e-mail address, and telephone and fax numbers, and other information necessary to respond to your request. ALIEN disclaims any legal duty to verify the accuracy of any personal data that you provide to ALIEN. 

Typically ALIEN will ask for you to submit personal data at the following times: 

  * Registration to gain access to certain areas of the site or for RFID Academy;
  * When we have to respond to your request for further information;
  * When we will need to distribute requested reference materials, products or services; and
  * Obtaining resumes submitted by you in connection with seeking employment; and

It is ALIEN's policy to collect personal data only when its collection is necessary. In any instance where non-mandatory information is sought, you will be notified of this at the point of collection. ALIEN's web site is not structured to attract children. Accordingly, we do not intended to collect personal information from anyone we know to be under 13 years of age. 

Collection of Personal Data by ALIEN Affiliates

When you link to the web site of an ALIEN affiliated, or an ALIEN sister company (or its subsidiary), referred to below as "ALIEN Affiliates", and you are asked to submit personal data, the data controller/administrator collecting the data for that web site or application shall be the applicable ALIEN Affiliate as described in any supplemental Privacy Policy information provided. In such instances, you may be asked to review to the appropriate supplemental Privacy Policy information and, if applicable, asked to complete and submit necessary consent forms to assure ALIEN's and each ALIEN Affiliate's compliance with the privacy laws, governing the collection and use of personal data in your country of residence. 

Consent To Collection And Use

By voluntarily accessing the applications, services or information provided to you by ALIEN and any ALIEN Affiliate on their web sites you acknowledge that such access is requested by you to facilitate our mutually beneficial business purposes. ALIEN and each ALIEN Affiliate therefore reserves the right to deny access to such services or information by you, where you decline to provide requested consent, if such consent is required by law in your country of residence in order for ALIEN or any ALIEN Affiliate to process or transfer the necessary personal data. You agree that by checking an "I Agree," "I Consent" or similar box, or voluntarily disclosing your personal data at an ALIEN web site, you may be deemed to have granted your limited consent to the mutually beneficial uses reasonably contemplated at the time of your consent, including ordinary data processing activities by third parties on ALIEN's behalf, to the extent such consent is legally sufficient in your country of residence. ALIEN ordinarily uses your data to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your data to update you on the benefits and features of ALIEN products and services and to provide you with information and material requested by you. From time to time, we may also use your data to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. At a minimum, we will always do our best give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such direct marketing or market research material. We will also follow internal requirements for avoiding the delivery of unwanted mail to you, such as allowing you to opt in before receiving unsolicited material, where applicable. 

Consent To Export of Personal Data

Where collection of your information may be deemed to be "exporting" your personal data under the laws of your country of residence, you agree that providing your personal information to ALIEN or an ALIEN Affiliate located in a jurisdiction other than your country of residence shall be deemed your express consent to the transfer of your personal information outside your country of residence, to that of the designated data controller/administrator, for the mutually beneficial uses reasonably contemplated at the time of your consent. 

Sensitive Personal Data

ALIEN's intention is not to seek any sensitive personal data through our web site. Sensitive personal data includes a number of types of data relating to: race or ethnic origin; political opinions; religious or other similar beliefs; trade union membership; physical or mental health; sexual life or criminal record. We suggest that you do not provide sensitive data of this nature, unless as part of an employment application. If you elect to provide sensitive personal data not requested by ALIEN, you expressly consent to ALIEN's use of that data consistent with the mutually beneficial uses reasonably contemplated at the time of your consent or as more specifically described at the point where you choose to disclose your personal data. 

Transfer of Personal Data

Personal data collected by ALIEN may be transferred to ALIEN Affiliates, which are member companies of the worldwide ALIEN organization, where it is necessary to meet the purpose for which you have submitted the information. By submitting personal data on ALIEN's web site, you are providing explicit consent to worldwide transfer of such personal data to, and use by ALIEN or any ALIEN Affiliate, within the scope of the privacy policies stated by ALIEN or any ALIEN Affiliates. 

Cookies

Cookies may be used on some pages of our site. "Cookies" are small text files placed on your hard drive that assist ALIEN in providing a more customized web site experience. For example, a cookie can be used to store registration information in an area of the site so that a user does not need to re-enter it on subsequent visits to that area. The use of cookies is intended to make navigation of our web sites easier for you and to facilitate efficient registration procedures. Cookies also enable us to monitor individuals' use of our site for the purpose of continuing to improve its usefulness. If you are concerned about cookies, most browsers permit individuals to decline cookies. In most cases, you may refuse a cookie and still fully navigate our web sites. 

Third Parties

ALIEN will not sell, rent, or lease your personal data to others. Unless we have specifically informed you, obtained your consent or are required by law, we will only share the personal data you provide online with ALIEN Affiliates and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf, and then only for the uses described in "Use of Data". If there is an instance where ALIEN may desire to share such information with third parties, you will be asked to consent to such disclosure at the time you submit the data. However, the sharing of such information will be made only for purposes consistent with the uses described in the Privacy Policy. 

Legally Compelled Disclosure

Despite ALIEN's commitment to protecting your personal data, there may be circumstances under which ALIEN may be deemed to be legally compelled to disclose your personal data. These circumstances may include, among others, situations where disclosure is required by law applicable to ALIEN, or necessary to comply with an order of a court or governmental agency, or necessary for matters of safety and security. In such cases, ALIEN will make good faith efforts to provide only that information which is the subject of the official order or request. 

Third Party Links

There are several places throughout the ALIEN web site that may link to other web sites that do not operate under ALIEN's privacy practices. ALIEN does not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. When you link to other web sites, ALIEN's privacy practices no longer apply and ALIEN assumes no responsibility for the information or other practices of a site that is accessible through ALIEN. We encourage you to review each site's privacy policy before disclosing any personally identifiable information. 

Data Retention

ALIEN does not retain all of the data that we receive. Contact information about visitors will be kept as long as the information is valid or until a user with appropriate authorization requests in writing that we delete that information. 

Your Choices

ALIEN respects your right to make your own choices about how your personal data is handled. Should you choose to subscribe to mailing lists or any registrations, and later decide to unsubscribe we will provide instructions, on the appropriate web site area or in communications to you or you may contact ALIEN at privacy@alientechnology.com. In addition access to certain applications or services may involve particular uses, disclosure or transfer of the personal information being collected during registration for that application or service. If required under the laws of your country of residence, you will be notified of such intended uses, transfer or disclosure and asked to provide your consent. Failure to provide you consent where so requested may mean you will not be provided access to the applications or services for which your personal information cannot be lawfully processed. 

Accuracy, Access & Further Notification

ALIEN strives to ensure the accuracy of your personal data, as provided to ALIEN. Depending on the privacy laws in your country of residence, you may have the right to view, update or correct data submitted through the web sites to ALIEN, or to receive additional notification of changes in the use of your information. When personal data is retained, ALIEN undertakes to make all reasonable efforts to maintain the accuracy of the personal information submitted and verified by you. ALIEN does not assume responsibility for verifying the information you submit, or for establishing the ongoing accuracy of the content of personal data. When practically possible, if ALIEN is informed that any personal data collected through a web site is no longer accurate, ALIEN will make appropriate corrections based on the updated information provided by the authenticated visitor. Queries in this regard should be directed to ALIEN at privacy@alientechnology.com. 

Security

ALIEN is committed to ensuring the security of your data. To prevent unauthorized access, misuse or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Sale of business assets

In the event of a sale of ALIEN, an ALIEN business unit, or an ALIEN affiliate, personal information held by ALIEN may be made available to a buyer or prospective buyers in order for them to evaluate any such purchase or to operate any parts of ALIEN's business. 

Modifications

Subject to the legal requirements of your jurisdiction of residence for notice and consent, ALIEN may at any time revise this Agreement by updating this posting and it's revision date. California law and controlling U.S. federal law govern any action related to this Agreement. Choice of law rules of any jurisdiction and the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods will not apply to any dispute under this Agreement. You and ALIEN agree to submit to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction of the state and federal courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California, U.S.A. Any express waiver or failure to exercise promptly any right under this Agreement will not create a continuing waiver or any expectation of non-enforcement. If any provision of this Agreement is held invalid by any law or regulation of any government, or by any court or arbitrator, the parties agree that such provision will be replaced with a new provision that accomplishes the original business purpose, and the other provisions of this Agreement will remain in full force and effect. This Agreement constitute the entire agreement between you and ALIEN relating to their subject matter. No modification to this Agreement will be binding, unless in writing and signed by an Officer of ALIEN. The efective date of this Privacy Policy is March 21, 2005.

Rev. March 21, 2005 

* * *

**** |  |
